SHANKAR SHARMA

Shankarsharma243@gmail.com | **└ +1 571-353-9485**

PROFILE

Over 10 years of progressive and hands on IT experience in Software Development, Design and Integration. Essayed roles of Technology Lead and Full Stack Developer on various projects utilizing a wide range of underlying technologies.

Excellent communication and leadership skills. Worked with various large-scale customers in the US to help them design and develop technology solutions for web applications and integration platforms.

TECHNOLOGIES & PLATFORMS

- Application Design, Development and Integration
- Language Java, Python, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML
- Framework Spring, Angular, Hibernate, React
- Automation Protractor, Karate, PACT
- Cloud Services AWS, Azure, CloudHub
- Application Servers IBM WAS, Tomcat, Wildfly
- Databases Postgres, DB2, SQL, NoSQL
- Integration Mulesoft, Azure Logic Apps, JBPM, IIB
- Miscellaneous Docker, Kubernetes, Web Services (REST& SOAP), Maven, GIT, SVN, Agile, JIRA, Confluence

EXPERIENCE

Navy Federal Credit Union - Senior Systems Engineer | Oct 2023 - Present

- Design & Development of e2e spring micro-service framework for member web portal
- Design & Development of APIs in Mulesoft RTF and Flex gateway
- Managing the Azure Kubernetes container orchestration

Fidelity Investments - Senior Software Developer | June 2023 - Oct 2023

- Design & Development of spring micro-service framework for market data
- Managing the AWS docker container orchestration

Hexaware Technologies (Client: Fannie Mae) - Senior Software Developer | April 2020 – June 2023

- Design and Develop software application interfaces using micro service architecture in Spring and Angular
- Automation framework development using Protractor
- API automation framework design & development using Karate & PACT
- Implemented application auth layer using Spring OAuth 2.0
- Design and develop re-usable cross cutting modules like logging, error-handling, health check

Avizva LLC - Software Engineer | June 2019 - April 2020

- Design integration flows using API led connectivity framework in Integration Platform as a Service (iPAAS) i.e.
 Mulesoft
- API and Micro-Services Design, X12 Edi Integration, flat file & SOAP based integration on Mulesoft Platform
- API Management & Administration using Anypoint Cloudhub, Design center and Anypoint Exchange
- Develop event driven frameworks across multiple sub systems to orchestrate the data flow using Apache Kafka
- API Modelling in RAML, Swagger using Microservices design frameworks
- Development of Jenkins pipeline to automate the flow build and deployment process

Avizva Solutions Pvt Ltd - Senior Associate Technology | June 2013 - May 2019

- Lead design & development effort for the Healthcare Integration & Visibility/Enrollment Management Platform using Spring, Angular and AWS
- Design and Develop workflow framework to automate the business processes and decisions in Software applications using JBPM
- Define Solution & Integration design for integrations with other partners as well as internal enterprise systems.
- Run requirement & design sessions with corresponding stakeholders & technology teams.
- Develop enterprise business rules using Drools and customized BR engine

PROJECTS

CIAM | Fannie Mae | Reston, VA | April 2020 - Present

This is a web application portal that allows Fannie Mae lenders to manage user access of Fannie Mae technology applications. Users can perform multiple operations via this portal i.e. Manage Access, Configuration Management, Broker/Admin Registrations, Manage Roles, Report Generations etc.

- Key Tech Stack J2EE, Angular, Spring, AWS, Protractor, Agile, Active Directory, Postgres
- My Role Senior Software Developer
- Key Responsibilities Re-usable framework design and development, Code review, OAuth2.0 implementation, Automation framework implementation, SSH key generation module implementation in Javascript, Dockerization of on prem apps

Liner Booking Integration | Crowley Maritime | Jacksonville, FL

This project includes Mulesoft integration with Salesforce portal for liner booking and shipment. Mulesoft was introduced as an orchestration layer between the traditional Datawarehouse and Salesforce to enable the flow of information from end to end.

- Key Tech Stack Mulesoft ESB, Salesforce, RAML based API Design & Development, SOAP & Rest Services, FTP, WMQ, Anypoint Platform & Cloudhub, Kafka, Dataweave
- My Role Development Lead
- Key Responsibilities Solution & Integration design, API and Micro-Services Design, Anypoint Cloudhub Monitoring & Runtime Management, Tech Design & Development

VaxCare Integration | WellDyneRx | Tampa, FL

WellDyneRx is a full-service independent Pharmacy Benefit Manager (PBM) responsible for managing Medicare Part D data for its clients. It processes drug claims and responsible for processing the remittance.

- Key Tech Stack Microsoft Azure Logic Apps, NoSQL (Cosmos DB), EDI, XSLT, Liquid
- My Role Senior Developer
- Key Responsibilities Design and Development of integration solution to process Medicare (EDI834) claims, remittance process (EDI277) and API framework to determine the eligibility, Audit framework implementation in logic apps with NoSQL (Cosmos) DB, Implementation of transformation modules (XSLT, Liquid) to generate EDI formats

Enrollment Rules Engine & Exchange Management Console | HealthPlan Services | Tampa, FL

The auto enrollment rules engine is an essential core component for the HPS exchange link strategy. The business rules engine validates and enriches data coming in from multiple source systems including CMS, insurance carriers and other insurance marketplaces. Complex enrichments include data population through logical computation by comparing incoming subscriber data with data present in the core systems.

- Key Tech Stack J2EE, Spring, WebSphere Technologies (WMB/WMQ), EJBs, SOAP services Design & Development, Spring MVC, SSO & LDAP based Authentication
- My Role Senior Developer
- Key Responsibilities Application development, Code reviews, Mapping & Design Documentations,
 Development guidance & co-ordination

SalesLink & Private Exchange | HealthPlan Services | Tampa, FL

Private Exchange is a cloud based multi-tenant platform that hosts 250 Private Insurance Exchanges selling Health, Dental, Vision, short term and Medicaid Plans. It has a catalogue of more than 40 US insurance companies serving 45 states with over 2000 Plans.

The platform is built using Spring framework on AWS. It integrates with 5 different external systems for Products and Plans, CMS Market Place, Rating Engines, Payment Gateways and Billing and Finance systems. It does SSO with major US insurance carriers and complies with HIPAA regulations.

- Key Tech Stack J2EE, Spring, React, AWS S3, AWS SQS, Redis Cache, SOAP services Design & Development, SOAP & Rest Services Integration, Spring MVC, SSO, Hibernate
- My Role Developer
- Key Responsibilities Application development

EDUCATION

- Master of Science, Sheffield Hallam University | 2011-2012
- Bachelor of Engineering, Maharishi Dayanand University | 2005 –2009
- Higher Secondary Education, CBSE | 2004
- Senior Secondary Education, CBSE | 2002